neb.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy | NEB

**Effective as of 5/15/2018**

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to provide information about how New England Biolabs, Inc. (“NEB”) collects, uses, and transfers personal information when you visit our website, [www.neb.com](https://www.neb.com/), our mobile applications, and other websites that we control that include a direct link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Sites”). Carefully review this document, as your use of the Sites is subject to this Privacy Policy. 

##  Scope 

This Privacy Policy covers only information collected through the Sites. It does not cover any other data collection or processing, including, without limitation, collection conducted offline, through other products or services that do not display a direct link to this Privacy Policy, or by other companies at third party sites that do not display a direct link to this Privacy Policy.

##  Information Collected 

In general, the types of personal information we collect include your contact information (such as name, company name, address, phone number and email address), and where relevant to fulfill a transaction or request, additional information such as billing or payment information, shipping addresses, end-user information, and credit card information. Additionally, in order to tailor our communications to you, we may ask you to voluntarily provide us with information regarding your scientific areas of interest, experience with our products, contact preferences, and other information. You provide us your personal information when you register on or submit information via the Sites, or otherwise provide us with or make available your personal information through other registration and data capturing processes, including other public sources of such data. In general, when you visit the Sites or interact with us in other ways you can refuse to supply personal information, with the caveat that it may prevent you from engaging in certain website-related activities. By providing your personal information, you agree that we may collect, use, share and/or transfer that information in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.  

We also collect information during your use and navigation of the Sites, such as the URL of the site you came from, the browser software you use, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, IP ports, date/time of access, data transferred, pages visited, amount of time you spend on the Sites, information about transactions conducted on the Sites, and other “clickstream” data. If you use our mobile app or access the Sites from a mobile device, then we also collect your device information (such as device OS version and device hardware), unique device identifiers (including device IP address), and geolocation data. This data is generated and collected automatically, as part of the standard operation of the Sites.

We use cookies, web beacons, tracking pixels, and other technologies (collectively, “Tools”) to collect information during your use and navigation of the Sites. A cookie is a text file that may be stored on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites. With cookies in place, our system will recognize you whenever you use your web browser to connect to our page. Disabling cookies may prevent you from using certain features of the site. If you choose not to take advantage of these interactive features, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie has been sent. 

##  Use of Information 

NEB uses your information for legitimate business interests, including to better understand your needs, fulfill orders, complete transactions, fulfill statutory or contractual requirements, provide requested services and information, and update you on products, services and benefits, which may include marketing materials. If you order products through our Sites, we may contact you by email to provide information about your order (e.g., order confirmations, shipment notifications, guidelines for how best to use the product, etc.). If you have an account with the Sites, we may also send you email regarding your account status or changes to relevant agreements or policies.

We use information passively submitted by you to personalize features and your experience of the Sites, and otherwise to generally improve the content, design, and navigation of the Sites. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may combine the various types of data we collect. We may conduct marketing analysis and similar research to assist us in making business decisions. Such analysis and research activities may be conducted through third party services, using anonymous data and aggregate statistics generated by our information collection.

In compliance with applicable law, we may use contact information that you have provided to send you information regarding products and services, as well as other information that we think may be useful to you. If you do not wish to receive marketing information from us, you may opt out (see “Opting Out” below).

##  Sharing/Transferring Personal Information 

In general, we share and/or transfer your personal information to affiliates, agents, vendors or service providers who assist us in the process of providing products or services to you, or otherwise perform functions on our behalf. We will not rent, sell or otherwise transfer your data to a third party for monetary consideration. We reserve the right to disclose personal information to third parties where we believe in good faith that disclosure is required by law, to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities, to comply with a judicial proceeding or legal process, or to protect the safety, rights, or property of our customers, the public, or NEB. If we sell or transfer a business unit or asset to another company, we may share or transfer your personal information pursuant to the terms of the transaction. In addition, we may disclose information about you to a third party at your request, or if you consent to the disclosure.

##  International Data Transfer 

Any personal information you provide to NEB, its affiliates, agents, vendors and service providers may be stored and processed, transferred between and accessed from the United States and other countries, which may not guarantee the same level of protection of personal information as the country in which you reside. However, NEB will handle personal information collected through a Site in accordance with the Site’s linked Privacy Policy.

##  Other Web Sites 

Our Sites may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our Sites, you should note that we do not have any control over other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection of any information provided while visiting such sites, and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and carefully review the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

##  Security 

We use commercially reasonable administrative, physical and technical measures intended to safeguard your personal information and help protect it from unauthorized access or loss. Users are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of their own passwords to access the Sites. However, no security can be 100% effective, and you should not expect that your information will remain private under all circumstances. If you have reason to believe that the security of your personal information has been compromised, please immediately notify us by contacting us at [ITinfo@neb.com](mailto:ITinfo@neb.com).

## Opting Out

If you do not wish to receive marketing information from us, you may opt out by: (1) declining marketing information when registering or at other information gathering points on the Sites, or (2) informing us that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications by emailing us at [NEBUnsubscribe@neb.com](mailto:NEBUnsubscribe@neb.com). We will comply with these requests unless such communications are required by law or contract or do not require your consent under applicable laws. If you would like to opt-out of receiving communications from affiliates or other third parties with whom we shared data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, please contact such third parties directly.

##  Children's Privacy 

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18. 

##  Data Retention and Access 

We retain data for at least as long as required by applicable law, and for periods of time needed for NEB to pursue our legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. You may access, correct, and/or update your information by accessing your accounts or profiles, where relevant, on the Sites. You may request a summary of information we hold about you, as well as corrections, updates or deletion of your information, by contacting us at [info@neb.com](mailto:ITinfo@neb.com). Our response to such requests will be limited to information under our direct control. We will make reasonable efforts to respond promptly to such requests in accordance with applicable laws.

##  Changes to Privacy Policy 

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time and in our sole discretion. Changes will be effective upon the date the revised Privacy Policy is posted on the [neb.com](https://www.neb.com/) website, with the effective date noted in the Policy header at the top of this page. When you visit the Sites, you accept the version of this Privacy Policy in effect at that time. We recommend that you periodically revisit and review this page to obtain the latest information on our privacy practices.

##  Contact Information 

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this Privacy Policy or privacy-related practices, please contact NEB via email at [info@neb.com](mailto:ITinfo@neb.com).

If you are located in the European Union or Switzerland and you have a data privacy or data use concern that you feel has not been fully addressed, you have the right to contact the relevant EU data protection authority or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner, as applicable.
